Sagar Vora

14 Snipe Lawn, Newcastle, Galway, H91CD58

+353 894897184 • sagar.vora03@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/sagaranilvora

PROFILE

Experienced Business Analyst with a six-year track record in investment banking and financial services, excelling in stakeholders' management, data analysis, dashboard creation and business requirements gathering. Proven success in crossfunctional collaboration and tailored solution provision. Committed to continual learning and rapid adaptation, poised to boost business efficiency and growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Project Management: JIRA, Confluence, Trello.

Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Microsoft Excel, R Studio.

Languages: SOL, Python, C#, R.

Tools: MS Office Suite (Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote, Outlook, Visio, and Word), Google Docs Editor, SPSS.

Frameworks: Agile/Scrum, Waterfall, Kanban, BPMN, SWOT, PESTLE, Business Model Canvas, Lean Canvas.

Functional Skills: Requirement Gathering, UAT, wireframes, user stories.

Soft Skills: Communication, Stakeholders Management, Problem Solving, Analytical Thinking, Decision Making.

Domain Knowledge: Financial Statement Analysis, Financial Modelling & Reporting, Credit Analysis, Compliance,

Covenants, Risk Reporting, Capital Budgeting, Liquidity and Valuation Analysis.

Financial Tools: S&P Capital IQ, FactSet, Reuters Thomson One, Merger Market, Deal Logic, Alacra, SDC, Debtwire.

EDUCATION

University of Galway

Galway, Ireland

MSc Business Analytics 1:1 Honors

September 2022 – June 2023

Database Management (SQL), Decision Theory and Analysis (Tableau), Data Science & Big Data Analytics (Retail Analytics), Business Applications Programming (C#), Systems Development & Project Management (Agile/Waterfall), Enterprise Systems (ERP, CRM).

Other Qualifications

University of Mumbai

Mumbai. India

Bachelor of Law (LL. B) - Criminology

October 2017 - October 2020 July 2014 - April 2016

Master of Commerce (M. Com) - Business Management

Bachelor of Management Studies (BMS) - Finance

July 2011 - April 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

ION Analytics (Debtwire) Business Analyst (Credit)

Mumbai, India July 2018 – July 2022

- Spearheaded requirement gathering, aligning stakeholders needs with business objectives and developed a performance evaluation tool, transforming team productivity with a 55% increase year-over-year.
- Created interactive data visualization dashboards using Tableau to consolidate static and unstructured rating actions data into thematic insights, enhancing data accessibility by 35%.
- Facilitated in formulating Business Requirement Document through collaborative stakeholders' engagement, aligning project deliverables with business objectives.
- Collaborated with data analyst to revamp the platform by integrating proprietary insights and data analytics to increase cross-selling of 3 products under leveraged capital markets.
- Facilitated active involvement in a pilot project aimed at developing industry's first proprietary tool using machine learning and statistical models capable of predicting distress scores for clients leveraging 15+ inputs.
- Influenced Scrum ceremonies, liaising with cross-functional teams throughout Software Development Life Cycle, using Jira for project management and requirements tracking.
- Employed business analysis techniques to generate over 80 reports, covering a wide range of sectors in North America including Retail, Services, Energy.
- Accelerated team efficiency by creating an automated peer company analysis template on FactSet, resulting in a remarkable time reduction of over 90%.
- Covered event driven situations like asset valuation for Macy's Inc to calculate market value of assets, increasing report impressions and click rate over 65%.
- Co-ordinated with subject matter experts, to gather insights used to produce special reports covering the impact of COVID-19 on Cruise Industry, increasing subscription rate by 4% year-over-year.

Citigroup Inc (CSIL)

Senior Executive

Mumbai, India

June 2014 - April 2016

- Led a team of 10+ members and documented business processes to deliver timely results to maintain effective relationships with project stakeholders.
- Gathered end-user requirements and managed workflow by creating user stories. Further scoped and delegated tasks, captured, and prioritized requirements using Citi's proprietary tool for successful project delivery.
- Developed research strategies and communicated with global coordinators or teams on an ongoing basis with respect to projects or assignments.
- Produced reports, conducted data analysis, and reduced the idle time to increase productivity of the team with consistent team utilisation rate of above 95%.
- Conducted retrospective meetings with senior management on operational and teams' performance metrics, including utilization, productivity, and adherence to deadlines, through regular and transparent communication.
- Thrived under immense pressure, demonstrating high level of accuracy by exercising independent thinking and balanced judgment.

VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE

REX Association

Mumbai, India

Volunteer

June 2016 - August 2017

• Assistance in fund raising activities, providing reading material and tutorials to children of low-income groups, and protecting the oceans by reducing plastic and marine pollution on the shores.

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

University of Galway President's Award (ALIVE) for volunteering.

Awarded Best Team for Design Thinking organised by SAP at University of Galway.

Certified Six Sigma Yellow Belt Professional.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Secretary of Business Analytics Society at University of Galway.

World of Code Hackathon organized by Lero at University of Limerick.

I-Days programme (Hackathon) managed by Ideas Lab at University of Galway.

Published an article in KC Law College annual magazine on Insolvency Bankruptcy scenario in India & related laws.

Interested in reading, sketching, painting, and following sports.

PROJECTS

Data Analysis and Business Intelligence – Leveraged clustering techniques, basket, and pareto analysis on point-of-sale data from a grocery retail store to drive decision making, extract business value, and formulate effective marketing strategies. **GHG Emissions Analysis** – Analysed greenhouse gas emissions dataset merged with economic indicators, yielding unique insights. Developed models to understand emission trends, tipping points, and risk mitigation. Offered actionable recommendations for future emission reduction.

Consulting Challenge (Business Process Redesign) – Revamped RFC's consumer loan system, implementing cloud-based application, automation, token-based repayments, centralized database, and OCR integration. Transformed loan processing, minimized errors, enhanced customer experience, and maximized efficiency for RFC.

Consulting Challenge (Enterprise resource planning) – Assessed failed ERP project, identified communication gaps, collaboration issues, and resource deficiencies. Proposed solutions: DevOps-Agile adoption, knowledge sharing, stakeholders' involvement, training, change management. Emphasized experienced consultants for successful ERP implementation.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.